Guide to the Gay Cable Network Archives 1982-2001 MSS 231
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series X: Gay USA
  - Subseries A: Cablecast Programs
    - 1996 Vol. XIV
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 3, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0178)
        10. Lou Maletta interviews Geoff Thompson, regarding his 1996 calendar “If You Want My Body” and the group home he runs.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 4, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0179)
        2. Interview: Christopher Lynn, Taxi & Limousine Commissioner, discusses a controversy regarding his pre-suspension of a taxi driver.
        3. African American Athletes, Success After Success: Nikki Franke
        5. Interview: Cheryl Schwartz, author, discusses her book “The Journey Out: A Guide for and About Lesbian, Gay, and Bisexual Teens”.
        COMMERCIAL: GMHC (Gay Men’s Health Crisis), “Fight the Fear”
        7. “Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Catherine Hanssens, Lambda AIDS Project Director, regarding recent HIV testing proposals.
        8. Lou Maletta interviews Lieutenant Grace Telesco and Police Officer Thomas Scaringelli, of the NYPD, regarding recruitment of new NYPD members.
        9. Clip of “Coming Out Under Fire” documentary regarding gays in the military.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 5, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0180)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Lee Sharmat discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes footage of Ed Koch regarding NYC Mayor Rudy Giuliani’s treatment of Ramon Cortines.
        2. Interview: Tom Beer, [filmmaker] with AIDS Community Television, and Kate Barnhart, activist with YELL and ACTUP, discuss Beer’s film “Peer Education, Not Fear Education”, in which Barnhart appears. Includes film clip.
        4. Footage of Carol Channing at [Champs].
        6. Clip from Tracey Ullman’s show [“Tracey Takes On…”]. Includes introduction by Andy Humm.
        COMMERCIAL: “A Living Memorial to the Holocaust Museum of Jewish Heritage”
        7. Footage of Men of Discipline anniversary party at The Lure.
        8. Entertainment News
        9. Footage of cast of “Hello, Dolly!” performing “One Night in Heaven”.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 6, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0181)
        Program content: LAMBDA
        COMMERCIAL: “Party”, at the Douglas Fairbanks Theatre
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Lee Sharmat discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes Headline News footage regarding a custody case between a lesbian and her convicted murderer husband.
        2. Interview: Steve Michael, Democratic Presidential Candidate, regarding his campaign.
        4. Footage of Rich Tafel, Executive Director of the Log Cabin Republicans, at an LCR conference regarding the rating of Republicans in Congress.
        5. AIDS News
        6. Lou Maletta interviews Phillip Matthews, Acting Executive Director of the People With AIDS (PWA) Coalition, regarding current HIV-related topics and issues.
        7. “Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Suzanne Goldberg, Lambda Staff Attorney, regarding a Russian lesbian named Alla Pitcherskaia who is seeking political asylum in the US.
        8. Entertainment News. Includes footage of Alice Walker on “Charlie Walker”.
        9. Footage of “All My Children”.
        10. Andy Humm promotes “Virgins and Other Myths”, a one-man play by Colin Martin.
        11. African American Athletes, Success After Success: Nikki Franke
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 7, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0182)
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 8, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0183)
        COMMERCIAL: AIDS Research Associates
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes NBC footage of Pat Buchanan, Republican Presidential Candidate, speaking in Manchester.
        2. Footage from CSPAN of discussion regarding same-sex marriage, hosted by the Los Angeles Freedom to Marry Coalition. Includes footage of Evan Wolfson, of Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund.
        COMMERCIAL: Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), “America Responds to AIDS”
        COMMERCIAL: National AIDS Hotline
        4. David Nimmons, Managing Director of Education at Gay Men’s Health Crisis (GMHC), and Carlos Cordero, from the [Community AIDS Prevention Activists], discuss CrossTalk, to be held at the Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center.
        COMMERCIAL: Ad Council, Earth Share, “It’s a connected world.”
        5. Beatrice Dohrn, Legal Director of Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with David Buckel, Lambda Staff Attorney, regarding violence against lesbian and gay youth in schools.
        COMMERCIAL: Ad Council, “It’s what in the world you can do”.
        6. Ralph Garcia, licensed physical therapist and doctoral candidate at NYU, discusses and requests volunteers for his research regarding stroke survivors.
        7. Entertainment News
        8. Footage of Community Health Project’s “Snowball” event. Includes footage of Lee Sharmat interviewing Kim Barget, chair of “Snowball”.
        9. Footage of [hypersexualized people and artwork].
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 9, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0184)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes CSPAN footage of Kenneth Bacon at Pentagon News Briefing regarding issues with “Don’t Ask/Don’t Tell”. Also includes NY1 footage of Norman Siegel, Executive Director of NYCLU (New York Civil Liberties Union), and Rudy Giuliani, NYC Mayor, regarding zoning laws that affect adult-themed businesses.
        2. Footage of Bishop Walter Righter on Nightline discussing the ordaining of openly gay men.
        COMMERCIAL: Ad Council, National Alliance for Research on Schizophrenia and Depression
        3. Interview: Ann Maguire and Sal Cecere, of the Irish Lesbian and Gay Organization, discuss the upcoming St. Patrick’s Day parade.
        5. Lou Maletta interviews Robert Kobel, of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), regarding tax issues that affect the gay community.
        7. Footage of the Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center’s 4th annual Music and Comedy Gala. Includes footage of Karen Williams, [comic]; the Flirtations, [a capella group]; Tret Fure and Cris Williamson, [musicians]; and Nell Carter [singer/actress].
        8. Lou Maletta interviews Doris Kloster, photographer, regarding her self-titled photobook.
        COMMERCIAL: “Support Human Rights for Lesbian and Gay People”, sponsored by Professionals in Film/Video. Includes Cathay Che of GLAAD.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 10, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0185)
        COMMERCIAL: Dan Gendron, Horologist, “Stop paying too much for antique watches”
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes clip of Andy Humm questioning Bob Dole, Republican Presidential Candidate. Also includes clip of young Bob Dole in POW camp during WWII. Also includes clip of Steve Forbes, Republican Presidential Candidate, on 60 Minutes. Also includes footage of Andy Humm interviewing Tom Duane, NYC Council Member, during protest of Republican bigotry. Also includes interviews with Charles Gargano, [Vice Chairman of the Port Authority of NY]; Mark Green, [NYC Public Advocate]; and Fred Hochberg and Mark Aurigemma.
        2. AIDS News. Includes footage of CNN [special] regarding how and possibly why AIDS affects different groups of people internationally.
        3. Andy Humm interviews Chris Bauer and Doug Robinson, Candidates for NYC School Board, regarding their platforms.
        4. Ralph Garcia, licensed physical therapist and doctoral candidate at NYU, discusses and requests volunteers for his research regarding stroke survivors.
        5. Entertainment News
        6. Footage of Gary Miller, Director, and Ann Hampton Callaway, singer, with the NYC Gay Men’s Chorus. Includes interviews with Miller and Callaway regarding the current program “With a Song in Our Heart” of Rodgers and Hart music.
        7. Lou Maletta promotes Andrew Barrett and Chris Burney’s Pop Diva Taylor Dane in “Archy and Mehitabel”.
        8. Lou Maletta interviews Dirk Shafer, Playgirl’s “Man of the Year”, regarding his personal life. Includes clip of Shafer’s film “Man of the Year”.
        9. “Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Suzanne Goldberg, Lambda Staff Attorney, regarding a recent victory in Portland, Oregon, on behalf of ACTUP protestors who had been illegally strip searched after being arrested at a demonstration.
        10. Footage of NYC Council General Welfare Committee from March 1986 discussing lesbian and gay rights bill. Includes footage of Tom Stoddard, co-author, Intro. 2; Andy Humm, gay activist; Joyce Hunger, of the NYC Human Rights Commission; and Patrick Silva, Attorney.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 11, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0186)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community.
        COMMERCIAL: abOUT Entertainment
        2. Footage of GLAAD Media Awards. Includes footage of Robert Wooley, auctioneer; Raquel Welch, actress; Barbara Walters, journalist; and Ru Paul, drag queen.
        3. Footage of 1996 St. Patrick’s Day parade and protests by Irish Lesbian and Gay Organization.
        COMMERCIAL: Imperial Court, Night of 1000 Gowns
        4. Lou Maletta interviews Robert Kobel, of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), regarding tax issues that affect the gay community.
        COMMERCIAL: AIDS Walk New York
        6. Entertainment News. Includes footage of JFK, Jr. quarreling in Washington Square Park with a lady friend.
        7. Lou Maletta interviews Jeffrey Friedman, Co-Producer and Co-Director of “The Celluloid Closet”, discusses the film. Includes film clips.
        8. Interview: Anthony Heilbut, author, discusses his book “Thomas Mann: Eros and Literature”.
        9. Lou Maletta interviews Joseph Cohen, author, regarding his book “You Know You’re Gay When…”.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 12, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0187)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm discusses recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes footage of Andy Humm and Lee Sharmat at St. Patrick’s Day parade, which includes footage of Tom Duane, NYC Council Member; Anne Maguire, of the Irish Lesbian and Gay Organization (ILGO); William Donahue, of the Catholic League for Religious and Civil Rights; Ed Sullivan, of the NYS Assembly; Gifford Miller, of the NYC Council; Louis Anemone, Chief of Department, NYPD; Cardinal John Joseph O’Connor, “Archbigot” of NY; Matt Foreman, of the Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project; Rudy Giuliani, NYC Mayor; William Bratton, NYC Police Commissioner; Ed Koch, former NYC Mayor; Al D’Amato, US Senator; Gerry Adams, of Sinn Fein; and Stanley Michels, NYC Council Member.
        2. Footage from NY1 of Governor George Pataki responding to call-in question from Andy Humm. Also includes footage of Andy Humm directly questioning Pataki, NYC Mayor Rudy Giuliani, and US Senator Al D’Amato [during St. Patrick’s Day parade].
        4. Clip of GLSTN [Gay, Lesbian, and Straight Teachers Network] video “Setting the Record Straight” regarding gays and lesbians in schools.
        5. Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Kim Kirkley, Lambda Staff Attorney, regarding the National Black Gay and Lesbian Leadership Forum’s recent annual conference in Dallas, Texas.
        7. Footage of Lou Maletta interviewing Delmas Howe, artist, at the Leslie-Lohman Gay Art Foundation regarding his exhibition “My Jesus Lives in Albuquerque”.
        8. Ralph Garcia, licensed physical therapist and doctoral candidate at NYU, discusses and requests volunteers for his research regarding stroke survivors.
        9. Lou Maletta interviews John Laub, artist, [at the Fischbach Gallery] regarding his artwork and personal life.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 13, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0188)
        2. AIDS News. Includes NY1 footage of youth AIDS activists at Board of Education regarding sex education.
        3. Ralph Garcia, licensed physical therapist and doctoral candidate at NYU, discusses and requests volunteers for his research regarding stroke survivors.
        4. Footage of Lee Sharmat at Empire State Pride Agenda’s Night of 100 Parties. Includes interviews with Laurie Dietz, [activist]; Mark Levine, [activist]; Mark Tadlock, [activist]; and Dick Dadey, Executive Director of the Empire State Pride Agenda.
        5. Entertainment News. Includes clip of Kevin Spacey at Academy Awards. Also includes NBC footage regarding Luciano Pavarotti’s sex symbol status.
        6. Footage of Perry Watkins, [gay military service member], speaking at the 1988 National Democratic Convention.
        7. Lou Maletta interviews Peter H. Duesberg, author, regarding his book “Inventing the AIDS Virus”, in which he denies HIV is the cause of AIDS.
        COMMERCIAL: Static
        8. Lou Maletta interviews Dan Kisner, President and Chief Operating Officer for Isis Pharmaceuticals, regarding a new drug called ISIS 2922 to combat the Cytomegalovirus (CMV) in AIDS patients.
        9. Clip of “The Ambiguously Gay Duo” sketch from The Dana Carvey Show.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 14, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0189)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes footage of the Gay Officers Action League (GOAL) announcing first ever lawsuit against police department for discrimination, which includes footage of Fran DeBenedictis, of GOAL; Edgar Rodriguez, [of GOAL]; Tom Duane, NYC Council Member; and Matt Foreman, of the Anti-Violence Project.
        2. AIDS News
        4. Footage of Lee Sharmat at the Tenth Anniversary of NYC’s Lesbian and Gay Rights Bill. Includes footage of Allen Roskoff, activist/recipient of Harold Pickett Award; Eleanor Cooper, [activist]; Andy Humm, gay activist and journalist; Steve Ziffer, [activist]/recipient of Harold Pickett Award; Joyce Hunter, [activist]/recipient of Harold Pickett Award; Arnie Kantrowitz, activist; and Janice Tomm, Co-Coordinator of Heritage of Pride ’96.
        6. Footage of “7th on Sixth” Fall 1996 Collections. Includes interviews with Clyde Jones, President of the Hetrick-Martin Institute, and Stan Herman, Chairperson of 7th on Sixth.
        7. Footage of David Downing, [musician], performing at Claire’s in Chelsea, NYC. Includes Lou Maletta interviewing Downing.
        8. Andy Humm discusses additional news events that relate to the LGBT community.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 15, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0190)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes NY1 footage of Cardinal John Joseph O’Connor, Archbishop of NY, discussing the tenth anniversary of the lesbian and gay rights bill.
        4. Footage from NY1 of William Fischer, openly gay teacher/activist, regarding his recent illness and AIDS.
        5. File Footage from January 1994 of Ilka Tanya Payan, actress, speaking about AIDS.
        6. “Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Catherine Hanssens, Lambda AIDS Project Director, regarding recent decisions on physician-assisted suicide.
        8. Lou Maletta interviews Rosa von Praunheim, Director/Author/Star of “Neurosia: 50 Years of Perversity”, discusses his film. Also includes interview with Fernando Cavelhosa, actor, discusses working with von Praunheim on “Neurosia”. Includes film clip.
        9. Andy Humm and Lou Maletta celebrate the 14th birthday of the Gay Cable Network.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 16, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0191)
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 17, [1996] (Box 12, Media ID: 231.0192)
        3. “Lambda Update”: Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Lou Maletta’s interview with Jennifer Pizer, Managing Attorney for the Western Regional Office of Lambda, regarding the freedom to marry and anti-gay marriage legislation pending in many US states.
        4. Footage of Lee Sharmat at Night of 1000 Gowns.
        5. Footage of Lee Sharmat at Legacy Foundation Benefit.
        6. Footage of David Petersen Award Presentation. Includes Lou Maletta interviewing Karen [Teemar], Director of Education for Body Postive.
        COMMERCIAL: Children’s Hope Foundation
        7. Interview: Peggy Shaw, actor, discusses the play “The Slow Drag”, in which she plays a man named Johnny Christmas.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 18, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0193)
        2. Footage of Marsha Scott, [of the Clinton Administration], and Bob Hattoy, gay activist, speaking at the Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center regarding President Bill Clinton’s candidacy for re-election.
        4. Footage of Gay and Lesbian Business Expo. Includes interview with Candace Gingrich, of the Human Rights Campaign.
        6. Andy Humm discusses the musical Rent. Includes muted performance footage.
        7. Lou Maletta interviews Marion Winik, author, regarding her book “First Comes Love”.
        8. Footage of “Cowboys, La Cage, & More” at the Blue Angel.
        9. Footage of Mr. Leather New York contest ’96. Includes footage of Andy Borden, Mr. Leather NY ’95; [Paul Zinser], Second Runner Up; Frank Quesada, First Runer Up; and Joe Gallagher, [winner of] Mr. Leather NY 1996.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 19, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0194)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes footage from NY1 of [NYS Attorney General Dennis Vacco] responding to call-in question from Andy Humm.
        2. Footage of event awaiting decision in Colorado Amendment 2 case [Romer v. Evans]. Includes interviews with Suzanne Goldberg, Attorney for Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund (Lambda); Beatrice Dohrn and Tom Stoddard, of Lambda; and Evan Wolfson, [Staff Attorney] for Lambda.
        3. Footage of 1996 Lambda Liberty Awards. Includes footage of Kevin Cathcart, Executive Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund; William Hibsher, [of the Board of Directors for the Hetrick-Martin Institute]; Jed Mattes, award recipient/former President of the Board of the Hetrick-Martin Institute; Urvashi Vaid, award recipient/former Director of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force; and Gerry Studds, award recipient/retiring openly gay Congressman from Massachusetts.
        4. Footage of PrideFest Philadelphia 1996. Includes footage of Malcolm Lazin, founder of PrideFest Philadelphia, and Donna Mae Stemmer.
        6. Entertainment News. Includes footage from Oprah interviewing Dennis Rodman.
        7. Footage of 4th Annual HX (Homo Xtra) Awards. Includes Linda Simpson, event hostess; Matt Foreman, [Executive Director] of the Anti-Violence Project/Special Honor Roll Award recipient; Kiki Herold, award presenter; Lady Bunny, Special Honor Roll Award recipient; and Varla Jean Merman, award presenter.
        8. Max Harrold interviews Michael Huhn, creator of “Peepshow” book, at the Leslie-Lohman Gallery.
        9. Footage of Black and Blue Ball 1996.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 20, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0195)
        COMMERCIAL: Thirteenth Annual Center Garden Party
        2. Footage of Andy Humm at the Lambda Literary Awards interviewing Bella Abzug, [activist and former politician] and Renee Roth, Manhattan Surrogate Court Judge, regarding the upcoming primary election.
        4. Footage of Andy Humm at the Lambda Literary Awards interviewing Mark Agrast, Congressional Aide for Gerry Studds, regarding AIDS funding.
        6. Footage of 5th Lesbian and Gay Photo Annual at the Leslie-Lohman Gay Art Foundation.
        COMMERCIAL: Centurions of Rome
        7. Footage of 1996 Lambda Liberty Awards. Includes footage of Jed Mattes, award recipient/former President of the Board of the Hetrick-Martin Institute; Urvashi Vaid, award recipient/former Director of the National Gay and Lesbian Task Force; and Gerry Studds, award recipient/retiring openly gay Congressman from Massachusetts.
        8. Interview: Rick Landman, [activist], discusses his work for the lesbian and gay community and promotes an upcoming commemorative event at the Gay and Lesbian Community Services Center.
        9. Late Breaking News: Lou Maletta discusses same-sex marriage issues.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 21, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0196)
        1. Lesbian and Gay News: Andy Humm and Ann Northrop discuss recent general events that relate to the LGBT community. Includes footage of [Christine Quinn, Executive Director of the Anti-Violence Project], and Tom Duane, NYC Council Member, at Sheridan Square for celebration of Colorado Amendment 2 [Romer v. Evans] decision.
        2. At the Sheridan Square celebration event, Lou Maletta interviews Suzanne Goldberg, of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, regarding the Colorado Amendment 2 [Romer v. Evans] decision.
        3. Footage of press conference for Vice President Al Gore at NY Hilton Hotel. Includes footage of Arlene Kochman, of SAGE; Danny Dromm and Maritza Martinez, activists from Queens; Dick Dadey, of Empire State Pride Agenda; Vivian Shapiro, of the Legacy Fund; Deborah Glick, NYS Assembly Member; Ron Johnson, NYC AIDS Czar; and Keith Cylar, of Housing Works.
        5. Footage of 11th annual AIDS Walk New York 1996.
        6. Interview: Leif Green, AIDS Walk Producer, discusses the Walk.
        7. Footage of the 10th Annual Emery Awards, the Hetrick-Martin Institute (HMI). Includes footage of Peggy Northrop, Board Member of the HMI; Jeffrey Banks; Stan Herman; Vivian Shapiro; Rabbi Sharon Kleinbaum; Clyde Jones; Andy Humm, recipient of the A. Damien Martin Award; Kevin Cathcart.
        COMMERCIAL: New York Lesbian and Gay Film Festival
        9. Lou Maletta interviews [unnamed], regarding the 8th annual New York Lesbian and Gay Film Festival. Includes clips of films “Everything Relative”, “Men Maniacs: The Legacy of Leather”, and “Scream Teen Scream”.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 22, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0197)
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 22, Atlanta, Georgia, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0198)
        2. Interview: Kate Kendell, Director of the National Center for Lesbian Rights, discusses her organization’s work and history in honor of its 20th anniversary.
        3. Entertainment News
        4. Footage of Troy Alexander at [SqueezeBox at Don Hills] for “Rock ‘n’ Roll Fag Night”.
        5. AIDS News. Includes “Lambda Update”: Beatrice Dohrn, Legal Director of the Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, introduces Catherine Hanssens, Lambda AIDS Project Director, speaking on telemarketers using lists of people receiving AIDS treatment.
      - Gay USA, Vol. XIV, Episode No. 23, [1996] (Box 13, Media ID: 231.0199)